<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Randall Krueger's Ethics Blog</title>
    <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Randall Krueger's Ethics reading assignments</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 5 Mar 2018 10:12:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://viice.github.io/blog/" rel="self" />


    <item>
      <title>Reading 07: The Invasive Advertisements</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading07</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 5 Mar 2018 10:12:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading07</guid>
      <description>There are many instances in which I have seen options to opt out of data collection for ads specialized to me.  I always take these options.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 06: The Snowden Case</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading06</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 22:09:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading06</guid>
      <description>Edward Snowden is one of the more controversial figures in modern American politics.  In 2013, Snowden leaked a lot of information from the United States government, primarily the National Security Agency, or the NSA.  </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project 02: The Reflection</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/project02</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/project02</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, the most important topic of all is the first one – start early.  I wish I had been building my resume from the moment I entered Notre Dame, working on hackathons, personal projects, and the like.  Another important part is the concept of doing extracurricular activities that you enjoy.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 05: The Responsibility to Prevent Errors</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading05</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:47:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading05</guid>
      <description>The Therac-25 accidents were a series of incidents in which patients that required radiation treatment were administered a much higher dosage than required, resulting in injury and death.  The incidents occurred when magnets used to spread a radiation beam were not engaged in combination with a higher power beam than desired being used.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 04: The Diversity Problem</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading04</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 12:19:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading04</guid>
      <description> In an ideal world, everyone would have the same opportunity and chance to have the same job, and in industries like the tech industry, there would be roughly the same number of employees of each race and gender. However, in our world, there exist inequalities that currently make this goal unreachable.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 03: The Burnout</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading03</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 2 Feb 2018 15:11:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading03</guid>
      <description>As mentioned by Max Schireson, it is very socially acceptable for a man to have a demanding job, spend most of his time away from his family, and miss out on a lot of his child’s growth. In contrast, Schireson mentioned several female CEOs who are constantly asked about their ability to manage their parental responsibilities while still maintaining their demanding job. While this is the case, I think it is possible for both men and women to have a fulfilling job while still managing their family life.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project 01: The Reflection</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/project01</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 2 Feb 2018 13:13:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/project01</guid>
      <description>The code of ethics is broken down into four main categories: honesty, responsibility, challenge, and passion.  The first two deal with academic integrity, encouraging students to do their own work, and work hard on it in order to learn and get the most out of their college education.  The final two categories are more personal, encouraging students to challenge themselves and to find their passion.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 02: The Interiew</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading02</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 11:14:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading02</guid>
      <description>My job interview process has yet to begin, but I’ve finished my internship interview process.  I will be interning with Epic Systems in Madison, Wisconsin this summer.  My interview process was very smooth, which surprised me, based on what I’ve heard from others who have gone through the process.  Most of the events that related to the interview process were very harmless, informational conversations about life at the company, that were not hard “grilling” of my knowledge of computer science.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 01: The Hacker</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading01</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 11:11:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading01</guid>
      <description>I have to start this entry off with discussion of the reading of “A Portrait of J. Random Hacker.” As I look through this paper, under each section, I feel like they cannot continue to describe me, and yet… each part I read, I find myself being able to say “yeah, that sounds like me, all right.” Even statements as simple as stating that the only team sport enjoyed by hackers is volleyball – the only team sport I played throughout school, save competitive gaming. The article nails my education, my religion, my dress, my politics, and even my favorite foods. This could easily be a portrait of me.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 00: Why Study Ethics?</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading00</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 21:11:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading00</guid>
      <description>As previously discussed in the first section of reading 00: in my opinion the three biggest ethical questions with regards to computer science are privacy vs. security, the morality of hacking an individual or government with the intent of saving lives and the ethical concepts relating to the creation of a powerful AI that has the potential to both help humanity and to hurt it. These issues make it important to study ethics if you plan on going into the field of computer science. The ACM code of ethics has imperatives that relate to each of these issues.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reading 00: About me</title>
      <link>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading-1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 21:11:00 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>https://viice.github.io/blog/reading-1</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am Randall Krueger, a junior at the University of Notre Dame, majoring in computer science. I will graduate in 2019 with a bachelor of science degree in engineering.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
